Inventory of the Oscar Stonorov papers, 1912-1978 (bulk 1929-1970)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Oscar Stonorov papers
1912-1978 (bulk 1929-1970)
Stonorov, Oscar, 1905-
04375
25.23 cubic ft. (56 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Contains materials documenting Stonorov's career as an architect and city planner.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged in six series. Most series are arranged alphabetically except for the correspondence, for which there is an alphabetical index.
Biography of Oscar Stonorov
Oscar [Oskar] Stonorov (1905-1970), an architect and sculptor, emigrated to the United States from Germany in 1929 and settled in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania in the early 1930s. He was interested throughout his career in public housing and affordable housing for the working classes. His architectural associates included Alfred Kastner, Louis I. Kahn, George Howe, and Frank Haws. In addition to numerous projects in Philadelphia and the northeastern U.S., Stonorov was the designer of the Frank Lloyd Wright exhibit which toured the U.S. and major European cities in 1951-1952. He was the principal designer of the United Auto Workers headquarters building in Detroit, Michigan and the UAW's Black Lake Conference Center in Onaway, Michigan. Stonorov and his long-time friend, UAW President Walter Reuther died in a plane crash in 1970 while inspecting the Black Lake construction site.
Scope and Content
The Oscar Stonorov papers document Stonorov’s career as architect and city planner. Much of the material pertains to architectural and artistic projects including Stonorov’s home (Avon Lea), the Carl Mackley Housing Project, Philadelphia city planning projects, exhibits such as “Frank Lloyd Wright“ and “Better Philadelphia,” and sculptures. Materials include drawings, notes, photographs, reports, and correspondence. The correspondence series chiefly concerns various construction and urban planning projects, but there is personal correspondence as well. There is an alphabetical index for the general correspondence.
The collection also contains speeches, papers, and articles written by Stonorov expressing his views on design and urban planning. In addition there is material from conferences, round tables, interviews, and forums with which Stonorov was involved. Also included are subject and research files and newspaper clippings on Stonorov’s work and colleagues, and biographical material such as resumes, articles about Stonorov, and photographs of him.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Oscar Stonorov at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Elizabeth and Katrina Stonorov, Frederick Gutheim, Nancy Grace, and Susan Cole between 1971-2005.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of select material from this collection are available at http://digitalcollections.uwyo.edu:8180/luna/servlet/uwydbuwy~79~79.
Access Terms
Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959 -- Exhibitions.; Grace, Nancy.; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959.; Gutheim, Frederick Albert, 1908-; Kastner, Alfred.; Olivetti, Adriano.; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.; Kahn, Louis I., 1901-1974.; Kaufmann, Arthur C.; Ragghianti, Carlo Ludovico.; Robinson, Hilyard R.; Haws, J. Frank.; Black Lake Conference Center (Onaway, Mich.); International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America|-- buildings.;; Architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Architecture -- United States.; Architectural practice -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Architecture -- Designs and plans.; Public housing -- United States.; Public housing -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; City planning -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; City planning -- United States.; Architects -- United States| -- Exhibitions.; Aging -- United States.; Sculpture, American.; Hosiery workers.; Architecture -- Exhibitions.; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Juniata (Perry County, Pa.: Township)
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Architecture; Politics, Government, and Law; City Planning
Container List
- Series I. Architectural Practice Files, 1930-1970
  Contains information on buildings, city planning, exhibits, and sculptures. It includes photographs, financial data and reports relating to projects.
  - Sub-series 1. Architectural Projects, 1930-1970
    Contains drawings, notes, reports, plans, photos, clippings, and correspondence for buildings and city planning projects by Stonorov and his architectural firms.
    - Albany Avenue Area Project (Hartford, CT), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Alley Dwelling Authority Project, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Annapolis, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Apartment House, Typical Outlay of, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Audobon Village Project, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Avon Lea (Stonorov Home), 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8-14)
    - Bacon, Edmund Home, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bannockburn Project, circa 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bloomingdale's Department Store, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Camden Housing Project Day Reports, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
    - Carl Mackley, Juniata Park (Hosiery Workers Housing), 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Carl Mackley, Juniata Park (Hosiery Workers Housing), 1932-1936 (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
    - Carl Mackley, Juniata Park (Hosiery Workers Housing), 1932-1936 (Box 51-52)
    - Carver Court, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Charlestown Elementary School and Playhouse Project, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Chester County Citizen's Housing, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Child of Tomorrow House, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Civil Works Administration (C.W.A.) Projects, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Clark, E.A. Project, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Clement T. Branch Village, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Container Corporation Project, circa 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Coward Shoe Store, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Crowell House Project, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Defense Housing Project, Camden, N.J., 1940-1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Detroit Civic Project, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Detroit Defense City Project, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
    - Detroit Leisure Activity Center, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Ecole Nationale Des Beaux Arts, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Forman, Dr. Clark, Living Room, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gimbel Brothers, Typical Floor Plan, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Gimbel's "Life" House For Family Living, 1941-1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Gratiot Redevelopment Project, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Harman Homes Project, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Hartford, CT renewal program for downtown, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Howard City Project, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - India Pavilion (New York World's Fair), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - India Pavilion (New York World's Fair), undated (Box 53)
    - Indian Project (Intercontinental Hotels), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Karlsruhe Baden, Germany Hospital, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Kelly's Oyster House Project, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Lansdale, PA, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lily Ponds Project, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Lombard Area Redevelopment Plan (Map), undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lower Marion Township (Map), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Luther Memorial Lutheran Church, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Martin Residence, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Meadville, 1930-1935 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company Plans, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Michigan State Fair, 1964 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1940-1954 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Miscellaneous Projects, 1940-1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Montcalm Farms, 1941-1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - National Capital Park and Planning Commission, 1944-1951 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Navy Yard, Philadelphia, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Neurology Department Proposed Plan, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - New Britain Housing Project, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - New Brunswick, Webb and Knapp, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - New York City Penthouse Additions, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - New York World's Fair, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Newark, NY Project, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Newark, NY Project, 1959 (Box 53)
    - Oak Lane Park, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Palazzo Strozzi Plans, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Park Street Area Project, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Patchell Estate Housing Project Plans, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Patterson, NJ Project, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Pease Woodwork Company, circa 1951 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Philadelphia City Plan, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - Philadelphia Gas Works Company, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Philadelphia Municipal Building, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Philadelphia Psychiatric Hospital, 1945-1949 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - Philadelphia Sport Stadium, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia Sport Stadium, 1964 (Box 53)
    - Philadelphia Union Health Center, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Philadelphia, University Redevelopment Area, Rolland R. Randall, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Phoenixville Hospital Project, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Phoenixville Housing Corporation, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Plamimetria Piazza Della Republica, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company Project, 1944-1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Plaza Apartments (Philadelphia), 1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Radbill Oil Company, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Radbill Residence Sketch, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Reinsel Residence, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Ribsam Drawings, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Row House Plans, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sarah Lawrence College Project, 1938-1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Schneck Memorial Buildings Dedication, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Sharon, PA Project, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Solar House Project, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Solidarity House, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Southside, Hartford, CT, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Southwork Plaza, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Palace Competition, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
    - Spooner House, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Steel-Frame House, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Stephen's College, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Strawberry Mansion Project, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Subsistence Housing, 1933-1934 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Tennessee Valley Project, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Tennessee Valley Project, 1934 (Box 52)
    - Tygart Valley Homestead, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified Map, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Unitarian Church of Southern New Jersey, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Warden, Mrs. C.A., Interior Room Plans, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Waverly Street, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Western Savings Fund Society Project, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Willow Run Project, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Yardville U.S.A. Project (McCall's Backyard Project), 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 18-21)
    - Yonkers, NY (Map), undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Youth Study Center for Girls, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Sub-series 2. Other Projects, 1933-1967
    Contains drawings, plans, correspondence, and press releases for exhibits curated and sculptures created by Stonorov.
    - Better Philadelphia (Exhibit), 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 24-25)
    - Better Philadelphia (Exhibit), 1940-1947 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Educational Housing Exhibit, 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Exhibit, 1949-1960 (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Exhibit, 1949-1952 (Box 12, Folder 1-9)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Exhibit, 1949-1952 (Box 55)
    - NCPPC Exhibit, Cororan Gallery, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Science Exhibit, Golden Gate International Expo, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Small Homes Embassy Non-Critical Exhibit, circa 1940 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Stephens College (Fountain Sculpture), 1960-1967 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Walter Reuther Bust, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series 3. Project Photographs, 1929-1962
    - Annapolis Home (R.L.F.), undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Beaver Falls, PA, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Better Philadelphia, 1939-1950 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Biological Lab of Highlands Museum, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Camden, N.J.- Westfield Acres, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Carl Mackley, Juniata Park (Hosiery Workers Housing), 1935 (Box 13, Folder 7-10)
    - Carl Mackley, Juniata Park (Hosiery Workers Housing) Glass Slides, undated (Box 56)
    - Coward Shoe Store, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Designs by Stonorov, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Exhibition, circa 1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Finkelstein House, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Karlsruhe, Germany Hospital, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Lake Houses, Stonorov and Willy Boesiger, Architects, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Lake Houses, undated (Box 56)
    - Low-Cost Housing, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Palazzetto dello Sport, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Sculpture, circa 1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Sculpture- Autmaw, Estate, Inverno, Primavera, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Steel-Frame House, 1935 and undated (Box 14, Folder 10-13)
    - Solar House, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Soviet Palace, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
    - Unidentified Glass Slides, undated (Box 56)
  - Sub-series 4. Supporting Materials, 1933-1970
    - Brochure Notes- Stonorov, Kahn, McAllister, Braik and Rosenfield, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Day Planners, 1935-1970 (Box 15-16)
    - Financial Information, 1933-1967 (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
    - Financial Information, 1940-1948 (Box 54)
    - Hearing, Commonwealth v. Stonorov, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Lease Agreements, 1934-1945 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, 1951-1964 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1934-1966 and undated (Box 17, Folder 2-7)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 19)
    - News Releases, 1934-1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Planning- General Notes, 1936-1938 (Box 52)
    - Reports, undated (Box 20, Folder 2-5)
    - Slum Clearance Materials, 1933-1934 (Box 52)
    - Work Agreements and Contracts, 1934-1959 (Box 20, Folder 6-10)
- Series II. Correspondence, 1929-1972
  Contains professional and personal correspondence
  - Alphabetical Index to General Correspondence, undated (Box 34-35 and 57)
  - General Correspondence, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 6-9)
  - General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-Sept., 1936 (Box 22, Folder 5-7)
  - General Correspondence, Oct.-Dec., 1936 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 2-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 6-9)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-July, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 10-12)
  - General Correspondence, Aug.-Dec., 1939 (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-Sept., 1941 (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
  - General Correspondence, Oct.-Dec., 1941 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 2-5)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-June, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
  - General Correspondence, July-Dec., 1943 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - General Correspondence, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 3-6)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-June, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
  - General Correspondence, July-Dec., 1945 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - General Correspondence, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 3-6)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-Sept., 1947 (Box 27, Folder 7-9)
  - General Correspondence, Oct.-Dec., 1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 2-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 6-9)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-Feb., 1950 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, March-Dec., 1950 (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - General Correspondence, Jan.-Aug., 1951 (Box 29, Folder 6-13)
  - General Correspondence, Sept.-Dec., 1951 (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
  - General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 5-12)
  - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
  - General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 10-11)
  - General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
  - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
  - General Correspondence, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
  - Telegrams, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, undated (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
  - Bauer, Catherine, 1934-1940 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Grace, Nancy (correspondence to), 1959-1966 (Box 36, Folder 2-8)
  - Grace, Nancy (correspondence to), 1967-1969 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Grace, Nancy (correspondence to), undated (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - Grace, Nancy (photographs from letters), undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Gutheim, Frederick, 1933-1954 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Perkins, Frances (Dept. of Labor), 1933-1937 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Reuther, Walter P., 1942-1964 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1949-1953 (Box 38, Folder 4)
- Series III. Writings and Speeches by Stonorov, 1930-1967
  Contains speeches and papers presented at various conferences. Also includes published articles written by Stonorov. Folder titles may reflect the paper title or the conference where it was presented.
  - Academy of Music, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "...And Housing", 1938 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Automobile Club of Philadelphia (speech to), undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - The Changing Family, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Colonisation of the Unemployed, undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - The Coming Reconstruction of American Cities, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Faith for Living, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - French Housing (speech), 1931 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - How Much House for Your Money, 1946 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - In Honor of Adriano Olivetti (speech), 1960 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Le Corbusier (Seen From America), 1946 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Leisure and the Community Center, undated (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Life, Liberty and the Pursuit of Architecture (speech), 1950 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Luther Memorial Lutheran Church, undated (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Meaning and Mechanics of the Demonstration Cities Program, undated (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Speeches, undated (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Neighborhoods for Family Living, (speech), 1949 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Olivier (speech), undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Peace Planning Commission, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia and Redevelopment (speeches on), undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Symposium on the Architecture of the City, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Theater and Places of Entertainment, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Urban and Family Living, circa 1955 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - World Hospital Congress, 1930 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1932-1967 (Box 39, Folder 9-12)
- Series IV. Professional Association Materials, 1933-1967
  Contains materials relating to international, national, and regional architectural issues with which Stonorov was involved. It includes transcripts from forums and roundtables; minutes, agendas, and proceedings from committees and conferences; materials from professional organizations; and other materials relating to Stonorov's involvement in issues on architecture and city planning.
  - Action Train, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1933-1952 (Box 39, Folder 14-15)
  - Architectural Forum Roundtable, 1955-1956 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Baltimore Museum of Arts, 1949 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Beaux-Arts Institute of Design, 1942-1943 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Beauty for America: Proceedings of the White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Betty Crocker Magazine of the Air (Radio Interview), 1948 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Bicentennial Conference I, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Buck County Park Board, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - CIAM, 1945-1951 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Citizens Development Committee, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Colorado College Conference, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Art Education, 1948 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Conference on Area Planning, 1948 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Housing for European Workers, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Urban Redevelopment, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Congresso Mondiale, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Cooper Union Forum, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1955-1965 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Discussion of a new role for public housing, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Experimental City Project, University of Minnesota, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Housing, 1933-1936 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - I.C.F.T.U., 1951-1952 (Box 41, Folder 14-15)
  - International Olympic Committee in Baden-Baden, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Ischia, Italy Conference, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
  - Istituto Nazionale de Urbanistica, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Forum, untitled, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous- Meeting minutes and professional organizations, 1943-1955 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Mutual Ownership Defense Housing Conference, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - National Conference on Slum Clearance, 1933 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - National Housing Conference, 1950 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - National Housing Center, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - National Public Housing Conference, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Pennsylvania Labor Standards Committee, undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Society of Architects, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Philadelphia Housing Association, 1943-1962 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia Housing Groups, 1934-1957 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Philadelphia Planning Commission, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
  - Philadelphia Symposium, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Symposium on Civic Design, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Symposium: Urban Renewal (Cleveland), 1961 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Symposium on Use of Operations Research in Urban and Regional Planning (Rome), 1966 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Transportation and the Regional City, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Urban Design Conference, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 8)
- Series V. Subject Files, 1912-1971
  - Sub-series 1. General Files, 1912-1970
    This sub-series contains information on Stonorov's colleagues, papers and reports written by others, photographs, and research on aging.
    - Bauer Wurster, Catherine, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition of Organic Architecture, circa 1951 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - George Howe and Associates, 1940-1945 (Box 43, Folder 11)